[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：编写一个计算简单数组表达式的函数exp。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Write a function exp that evaluates simple array expressions.
一个简单的数组表达式是一个数组，其中第一个元素是一个函数，并且
A simple array expression is an array in which the first element is a function and
其余元素是该函数的参数。
the remaining elements are the arguments to that function.
所以如果我们传递数组，mul，5，
So if we pass that array, mul, five,
11到EXP函数，它将返回55。
11 to the EXP function, it will return 55.
如果我们简单地将一个数字传递给exp函数。
And if we simply pass a number to the EXP function.
它只会返回那个号码，好吗？
It will just return that number, okay?
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：二进制？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Binary?
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：是的，但有些是二元函数。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Yeah, but some are binary function.
事实证明，它也可以与一元函数一起工作，但是-
It turns out it will also work with unary functions, but-
&gt；&gt；演讲者3：下一步是什么？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: What's the next?
对，例如。
Right, exp.
对不起。&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：是的。
Sorry. &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Yeah.
是的，你是对的。
Yeah, you're right.
&GT；&GT；扬声器3：它总是对的吗？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: And it's always right?
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：可能是两个或三个。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Could be two or three.
&gt；&gt；扬声器3：两个或三个，好的。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Two or three, okay.
&GT；&GT；道格拉斯·克罗克福德：但你并不关心这个。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: But you don't care about that.
假设三个，总是这样。
Assume three, it's always.
&gt；&gt；扬声器3：当然。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Sure.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：明年会是n，但是。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Next year it'll be n, but.
&gt；&gt；扬声器3：好的。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Right, okay.
&GT；&GT；道格拉斯·克罗克福德：但今年将是三个。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: But this year it'll be three.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：好的，这是Exp。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Okay, here is exp.
EXP接受一个值，如果该值是一个数组，则返回一些值。
Exp takes a value and it returns something if the value is an array.
它返回调用第一个元素的结果，
It returns a result of calling the first element,
将接下来的两个元素作为参数传递。
passing the next two elements as arguments.
否则，它将返回值。
Otherwise, it returns the value.
那么，谁有用的东西呢？
So, who got something that works?
非常好。
Very good.
想再来一次吗？
Wanna do one more?
你以为你有这个本事吗？
You think you've got it in you?
它将基于这个，所以
It's gonna be based on this one, so
如果有人没有得到这个，现在就得到它，因为你会需要它。
if anybody didn't get this one, get it now cuz you're gonna need it.
准备好了吗？
Okay ready?
最后一个问题。
Last problem.
完成强可以这样。
Finish Strong OK so.
修改x P
Modify x P.
来计算嵌套数组表达式，这就是OR表达式。
to evaluate nested array expressions and that's that or expression is.
就像简单的表达式一样，除了
Just like the simpler expressions except
任何参数也可以是嵌套数组表达式。
any of the arguments can also be a nested array expression.
所以在这种情况下，我们有一个斜边的东西在这里进行。
So in this case, we've got a hypotenuse thing going on here.
如果我们将嵌套数组结构传递给exp，
And if we pass that nested array structure to exp,
现在它将评估整个事情并得出5个结果。
it will now evaluate the whole thing and come up with 5.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：每个人都明白了吗？
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Everybody got it?
[BLACK_AUDIO]&gt；&gt；扬声器3：获取一个参数是
[BLANK_AUDIO ] &gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Getting one parameters is
如果对数组求值，则可以传递给数组。
an array, can that pass of, pass to if it's evaluated.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：是的。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Yes.
完全正确。
Exactly.
所以让我们来看看exp。
So let's take a look at EXP.
所以我做的唯一的改变就是我调用了exp
So the only change that I made was I called EXP
在我们使用它们之前，请先对每个论点进行讨论。
on each of the arguments before we use them.
就是这样。
That's it.
因此，递归最终完成了所有的工作，这真的很好。
And so, recursion ends up doing all the work, which is really really nice.
无论何时您正在处理嵌套数据结构
Anytime you're dealing with nested data structures
递归通常是处理该问题的理想方法。
Recursion is usually the ideal way to deal with that.
所以这个函数说明的好事情之一就是它有多强大
So one of the nice things that this function illustrates is just how powerful
功能系统可以。
function systems can be.
其中的这个小功能是一个小功能
That this little function in it is a little function
实现编程语言的大部分内容。
Implement most of a programming language.
有人认识这是什么语言吗？
Anyone recognize what language this is?
列表，是的，在列表中他们使用
List, yeah in list they use
父代而不是括号和逗号是可选的，否则这是Lisp。
parents instead of brackets and the commas are optional otherwise this is Lisp.
这显然不是整个语言，但它是语言中一个有趣的部分。
It's clearly not the whole language, but it's an interesting part of the language.
做Lisp的人这样做的原因之一是因为
And one of the reasons why people who do Lisp act the way they do is because
他们可以做这样的事情，真的很快，真的很容易。
they can do stuff like this really, really fast, really, really easily.
只是，你把它比作实现
It's just, you compare that to implementing
一个系统来做我们的语言之一。
a system to do one of our languages.
这是一件完全不同的事情。
And it's just a completely different thing.
所以我希望你们都喜欢这个。
So I hope you all enjoy this.
今天很累，但是
Today was grueling but
你出来了，有没有人觉得今天他们的大脑变大了？
you came out, does anybody feel like their brain got bigger today?
有人感觉到了吗？
Anyone feeling that?
所以在我送你回家之前，显然你需要一些家庭作业，对吗？
So before I send you home obviously you're going to need some homework right?
所以让我们开始做作业吧。
So let's get to the homework.
家庭作业问题是编写一个函数ADD G，该函数用于添加
The homework problem is write a function add G that adds for
多次调用，直到它看到一个空调用。
many invocations until it sees an empty invocation.
当您收到一个空调用时，当您接收未定义的参数时。
When you've got an empty invocation when you receive undefined as an argument.
因此在这种情况下，如果没有传递任何内容给add G，它将返回undefined。
So in this case if you pass nothing to add G, it will return undefined.
如果你通过了两个然后就什么都没有了。
If you pass two and then nothing.
它将返回2。
It will return 2.
如果你传递2，然后是7，然后什么都没有，它将返回9。
If you pass 2 and then 7 and then nothing, it will return 9.
如果你传递3，然后是0，然后是4，然后什么都没有，它将返回7。
If you pass 3 and then 0, then 4, and then nothing, it will return 7.
如果你通过1，然后是2，然后是4，然后是8，然后什么都没有，
And if you pass 1 and then 2 and then 4 and then 8 and then nothing,
它将返回15。
it will return 15.
所以我给你个提示。
So I'll give you a hint.
这个问题将涉及一个函数返回自身，
This problem is going to involve a function returning itself,
这可能是你以前从未遇到过的事情。
which is something you may have never encountered before.